All right, let's do it. Nestor, you had some questions about
pricing? Yeah.
Yes sir. The pricing ma may.
Okay. Do you have a website you want us to look at? Do you have a,
or you just want go through the I
Actually do. So this is uh,
a client that I recently closed and I closed them for
a technical sprint.
And so I wanna see where I can take this moving forward in the
next couple.
Okay. Yeah,
Go ahead. Yeah, I'm just typing it in. Typing the U R L. All right, perfect.
That should work.
Okay. All right. So let's see here.
So you said you did a technical foundational sprint for them? Yes,
That's what I'm currently doing right now.
Okay, so they got nothing here. Yeah. Okay.
And what did you find as a result? Have you finished that? I'm halfway through
With it. I, I found the keywords so far.
I found their main keywords during the free analysis that I did for them.
So if you scroll down,
they already have it on their house buyers from in San Antonio and
I believe that, so I just quickly typed that in on HFS and found the,
we buy houses in those cities.
So I have an idea since I've done this before and this is my target audience,
I have an idea of what I'm going to build out, but I haven't,
I haven't gone through and done a deep analysis yet.
Okay. Yeah, we have this client called SoCal Home Buyers.
We just resigned them actually we worked with 'em a couple years ago and then
I've seen them before.
Yeah, so this is a client, um, so we worked with them. Yeah.
See how clients are and then they decide to take things into their own hands.
You see what happens. So we started working again, picking it back up.
So it's literally the same, that's the same vertical here, right?
So I can just tell you exactly how we've scoped this out and done this deal.
Just content link building.
I think the key here is just understanding how the site needs to be
structured in terms of like how do they,
because this is an interesting space, right?
They're never gonna get re verified Google business profiles and all these
locations. But I also don't think that you have to for the most part,
'cause like for example, if we say sell my house,
my like fast Miami is not a big one too. Well I guess there are some GSS here,
but for the most part you get these all the same types of sites, right?
It's like look at this one here, the buy guys locations, Florida, Miami.
So what that tells me is that they've just got these content subfolders. Yeah.
On Florida they probably got a sub folder here Florida, all the Florida cities,
right? And then they probably got a location splash page as well, right?
So they've got a search bar, you can search for it, et cetera.
So essentially what you're gonna need to do is create a lot of content for
this website.
But I think the key thing is identifying the right markets,
right? That a, that they want to be in. So right,
this is not gonna be a national campaign overnight just because they don't have
the authority to rank for all these different locations. Have you, am I,
have you already started to like find this and make these recommendations or
like document these I should say on W Q A or anything like that?
Yes, I have. Okay. So that I've done that.
I just haven't gone in and done the keyword research in depth. So that's,
I have to do that this week.
Okay.
So what I would do instead of keyword research and here we can start to segue
into the pricing of the campaign, right? And let me actually pull open one,
get a pricing on this.
So with a website like this where there's basically no existing traffic,
no existing pages,
the W Q A isn't really gonna turn up a whole lot aside from like a site map,
right? Yeah. So what you're gonna want to do then,
instead of Q research is what I call like kind of page mapping where you're
basically building out and recommending the right website architecture,
which is essentially just looking at like websites like that we talked about
already, right? Yeah. So like where are we, how it works,
recent projects calls from, this is the right one, oh sorry,
I'm on the wrong website. This one where it has locations, right?
And so basically just building out this architecture for them or demonstrating
it like when I say build it out like in like a slide document or like a MIRO
board or something along those lines, right?
Where you can just visualize like top level application pages and then the
content structure underneath and then the scoping of this becomes very easy.
It's just them based on your knowledge and expertise,
how many pieces of content do they need over what time period and how many links
do they need and over what time period. So Got it.
What I would do then is where are they located? Okay,
you said they're in Texas, right? Texas.
So I would focus on the Texas markets first, right?
The Texas local markets. And then, so if you like there's, excuse me,
there's a couple of ways you can approach this.
One is based on what you know that they can pay or are willing to pay so you
don't break their bank. 'cause you could go to them, this could fly,
the scope could fly off the handle for this very quickly, right?
In a perfect situation world you'd be like yo,
we want to attack every single market in Texas, right?
And then all leave the future availability to go into new states as well.
What I mean by that is setting up,
and this is where like your documentation becomes so important.
What I mean by that, so you can see they have three sub-folders here.
They've got a locations folder, they've got a state folder,
they've got a city or a call it final location folder, right?
Yeah.
This is the proper way to do it if you wanna scale nationally or globally
because this allows you to build all this content by state underneath locations
super easy, right? So we go back to, I don't have a full one here,
but even when we go to flip,
they've got the splash page and then they've just left these open.
What they're probably doing is the same thing.
They're probably looking at a state market now 'cause they're national,
they're probably crushing it. What are the highest search volume areas?
And we just prioritize based on that or the highest,
like also not just search volume,
but also I would say like most affluent, right?
Because I'm assuming the OR or maybe non-affluent,
maybe they want to buy houses and beat up neighborhoods that are cheaper.
I don't, you'll have to talk to the client about that.
But this is part of the conversation that you have with 'em in terms of helping
them understand what the strategy is off the back of the foundational sprint.
So like showing them websites like this,
showing them what like the pie in the sky looks like and then showing them the
roadmap for how they get there. And that becomes a scope basically.
And that's a beautiful thing about this system is that like when we talk about
reselling more sprints, we're not selling them something that they don't need.
We're selling them stumping.
That's something that's like perfectly scoped out based on the work that you're
doing now.
So this just becomes a matter of them deciding what they can spend and if
they're like, yeah, necessary this is great,
but like we can't spend more than x per month,
then you just prioritize based on that. So for example,
if you go in and we're saying that they're,
you set up a locations paid for them, right? And or you go to them and say Look,
do you have a plan on expanding outside of Texas? And if they say no,
then you could just make this subfolder Texas and literally just rip this page
here where it's a list of all the cities exactly like this that they wanna rank
in and then you go into the local markets like that, right? But if they're like,
yeah, in the future we wanna leave it open to expand,
then you can create the sub fuller that's locations state and you just make
Texas the only one that's available right now,
but that gives you the ability to go into more states in the future.
You know what I'm saying?
So during our discovery call, the the my client,
they said that they want to eventually expand into Florida.
So she's currently in Texas,
but she said within the next year or so she wants to get into the Florida
market.
Okay. How that's,
so that tells me what I need to know here in terms of setting up a locations
page. But again, still maybe only you could still,
you could still just do Florida sub folder too, right?
You don't have to do locations page,
it's more of if they plan on expanding nationally and I would say just based on
where they are now, right? In terms of going into Florida sounds great,
but like realistically it doesn't look like this company has too much cash flow
to like really put too much resource into that just because I know that these
companies like they live and die off of organic traffic.
It's the only way to really scale these comfortably.
Either that or they're just banging on houses and cold calling.
That's to try and get people to sell.
That's correct. That's correct.
That's what she told me that she's been doing and it's been successful for her
is just the old school way of just knocking on doors, cold calling.
So now she wants to invest into her digital marketing. Yep.
She also asked me if I do P P C. Yeah.
So I guess she's getting tired of doing all that hard work.
She's already hired people to do it for her,
but now she wants to have people come to her versus her going to of course
Scales more.
Yeah. So I know she has the budget.
Yeah, so looking at this one, the buy guys, yeah, they're doing pretty well.
I wonder if they're paying for traffic too. I would do paid here too, right?
It's just gonna be the fastest way to turn around stuff.
But organic is actually probably gonna be cheaper in this instance. So yeah,
I would look at this website, the buy guys right? As one that,
so they actually might only be in, it looks like they're only in Florida,
Georgia, Alabama. So again,
I would look at this website in terms of how you structure the architecture of
the website.
And then from there you can also look at literally if we go back to
like their, where's Miami? We look at their Miami page,
you can get a sense for what the scope of the content needs to be. Yeah.
Look at anything. Anything too crazy. And then you just say look at,
so we identified 20 cities or markets in Texas
that they all need their own dedicated landing page.
It all requires unique content. We can do it for you at, I don't know,
$500 per page, right? Whatever that looks like.
Whatever you wanna scope that with. So 20 times five is 500,
so that's $10,000 for compliment right now if you tell her.
And then plus the links too, right?
Like you just do the research and see it's not really like this simple,
but like hypothetically, right? If we say okay,
what does it take from a pure link point of view at that page level? Yeah.
For this company to rank in Miami, they might have no links, right?
Because a lot of times they just have the authority that passes through.
So they have 30 referring domains to this Miami page alone. And let's see,
oh they're actually in Texas too, right? Am I right? I think I did see that.
Yeah. I think they're in Texas so we could actually look, no,
they're in Florida, Georgia, Alabama. But okay,
so overall 170 we're referring domains. That's nothing,
that's not insurmountable.
But like this is a brand new website that you're working in in an industry that
like Google doesn't love.
So you're gonna want to figure out some sort of maybe natural link building
method to like pad first right before you just start hammering it with no BSS
links. That would be my advice.
Could potentially even recommend like a PR campaign if she's got any sort of
budget. But this is like a tough space for pr. This is just like a,
I don't wanna call it like a dirty industry,
but like this is just one that Google just they know that like you don't really
need a physical office or location in order to like spam the results just like
this company's doing. Got it. So Connor asked,
do you have any info on natural link building tips? Yes.
So PR RO would be one example, but Connor in your industry,
that's probably just gonna be too expensive. Another one,
let me see if I have this open here real quick from my link pm
Sorry, bear with me one second.
So what I asked him to do a while back September, maybe this is it.
So for law firms,
I had asked him to basically put together a list of legal
link opportunities that are like directories
and I don't wanna call 'em citations, but if we open one of these up, right?
Like National association, uh, criminal defense lawyers.
And then I had him go through and tag it with,
if it's a profil link where they can submit it for blah blah blah if it's paid
or free, whatever and if it's followed or not.
So this is like a pretty good example. He's just, this is a guy that we use.
He's, I dunno if you call him a va but like he handles all of our link building.
He basically works with, works through he's,
he works for us probably halftime and he manages no bss our target pages.
Like anything links,
we basically just build him a list of links in Asana or spreadsheets, whatever.
And he just manages no BSS on our link vendors.
So I asked him to do this as well.
And this is like something that we're now working on implementing for newer law
firm websites that don't have any kind of like authority, right?
We're doing this for them or we're asking them to do this for themselves.
So this is a good example of just doing some research on certifications on
profil links,
directory links that they're just like natural good just shows that like you've
got a good base for your business and then after you go through something like
this then you can start thinking about hammering them with more,
with more like no BSS style SS e o links, quote unquote. So anyways,
nester back to this just to wrap this up for you.
So you scope out content and links and then you go to them and say,
hey look at this is what I'm scoping out for you to rank in these markets.
And then if she's, whoa, this is more than I thought.
It's okay we don't have to pay this upfront.
We can spread this out over the next 12 months.
We could spread this out over the next six months. So she's,
I only have 2000 bucks a month to spend, then we can say okay,
that means we can do three pages a month and two links or we can do four pages a
month or maybe if we could bump it up to 3000 then we can do four pages a month
and four links. And I think that'll be like a pretty good velocity. So Awesome.
Yeah, so don't get caught up too much on the actual spreadsheet side of this.
It's really just a way to demonstrate it.
That's why doing the foundational sprint of the technical sprint as a standalone
trip wire, so effective because you're getting,
basically getting paid to do the scoping, right? Yeah.
Because a website like this, you're not gonna find too much,
but you're basically just saying, okay, here's what we found.
I now know exactly what we need to do in order to get you the results.
We'll clean up any issues that you might have,
but now it's time to start creating stuff. You know what I'm saying?
So I have a question. Yeah.
Would you recommend fixing the issues during that month one or
What type of issues have you found?
So the biggest issue that I did find is that they had their domain
linking to a different content hosting.
So I think they used to, they used to operate under carrot and now they're okay
Yeah I know Kara, yeah, I'm actually familiar with them in the space.
So now they're working at, now they,
and they switched over to minute pages but when they did that they never
redirected the location pages that they had on Carrot.
So they have a bunch of lost links from their websites that I would have to put
back together.
Yeah, I would definitely do that.
So that's the biggest issue that I saw on the technical side.
Yeah. And if they're, yeah,
I mean if they're budget like conscious and I would just do that as a part of
the foundational sprint, just knock it out, get it done.
It'll probably have somewhat of an impact.
'cause then you can buy yourself some, I won't call goodwill,
but that should have somewhat of an impact maybe and you can use it to point to
as a result of your services, which helps you to sell more stuff. Okay,
Awesome. That definitely answers my questions.
Especially the part where you said that I can scope down the amount of
location pages that I can make for them within a month. Because I remember I,
I watched a couple of videos of yours and I remember in one of them you said
that the, that you usually,
I think you said that your content sprint would be like 10 pages per month or
10 content briefs per month. So that kind of helps. Like I don't have to do 10,
I can actually scope it depending on what the client needs.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Cool. Anybody else? We've got questions. No, yeah,
I got a question.
Yeah, fire away.
Hey, so about six days ago I'm like on the verge of really big,
like the biggest deal in my life.
It's 4,000 a month for 12 months and he to send over the agreement and that he
had every intention of moving forward. And then six days ago,
I think you guys remember like he asked for the W nine and so in this case I
haven't heard from him and he'll ghost me for a week or two weeks and then he's
just on a different time zone. It's insane.
And so I'm just curious 'cause I know you were saying like follow up like a bat
outta hell just like every single day.
But I mean in this case like knowing all of that,
do you think I should like lay low and let him do his thing?
Or is this still loss potentially? 'cause it got me crazy.
It's a fine line, right? I totally under, like I said before,
like from the point of a prospect,
I hire contractors and vendors all the time.
There's a video editing company that's been sitting in my inbox now for two
weeks that I'm like, I want to work with them but like the,
the mental bandwidth that I know that it's gonna take me to hire them and
onboard them and migrate my content over. And it's just,
it's overwhelming to think about.
So it's one of those situations where a big deal,
a big scope like that,
it's probably something that like you have to be s like fully aware of and
focused on. But what I mean, okay, so you've only talked to him via email.
Do you have his phone number?
Yeah. Yeah. So I called him today and I left a voicemail and that's the thing,
it's weird like I,
this started two and a half months ago and then he ghosted me for a month and
then randomly appeared and was like, hey, like I have some more questions.
And I'm like cool. So I sent him an appointment link and he literally took,
I'm not exaggerating, an entire week just to schedule an appointment.
Mm-hmm And then he pushed it back another week after he already scheduled.
So then like we talked on the phone and then so it's just been like that he just
disappears and then just reappears again.
But he seems very interested and to the point where he literally said, yeah,
I intend to move forward, send me over the email.
Yeah, it's one of those situations man,
where like when you've got a lot of deals in the pipeline then it just becomes
part of the pipeline. But I understand if this is like a huge deal for you,
then it can become like a focal point for you.
I would say that if you've already called a up a voice note,
like there's only so much that you can do.
Like sometimes it just is what it is. Like I said, I mean he,
he like I understand that too again what he's going through where it's,
I really wanna do this but like I have a lot going on right now and for me to
dedicate that the CO even just like to sit down and sign it review like all that
stuff. And that's also why like agreement,
they can definitely slow down deal velocity,
especially for bigger companies 'cause they're like,
oh f**k now I gotta send this to my attorney and read this.
It's just like a lot of mental bandwidth that I think we have to be a little bit
mindful of that we take, even though we're here to take work off their plate,
like the onboarding process is a little bit intense.
Like we need information from them. Especially like stuff where they're like,
I don't even know what the f**k Google Analytics is and like they're asking me
to do this. It just, it becomes a lie.
I don't think there's a whole lot that you can do at this point because you
don't wanna, you don't wanna push 'em away. I just think oh,
oh follow up with 'em every week, call text, just be like, Hey Michael here.
Just wanna make sure that everything's cool.
We're standing by ready to get start,
you know like all we need from is a signature, we'll take care of the rest.
We don't require anything on your part. And the longer we wait further back,
we're pushing this campaign.
So like all we need is your signature or even just be like we can get started
without it too. If the agreement's holding up, I don't know, we're like,
but like we're itching to get started,
the team is ready so that way he'll be like, he'll at least give you a response.
It'll be like okay then no I don't wanna do this now or 'cause I,
because I agree just letting this drag on for forever. It's not,
it's actually better to get like a no not right now,
follow up with me in six months then have him just keep on dragging out like
this, you know? Yeah. Uh, go ahead Noah.
Something that I try to do that works fairly well for me when I've got people
like this where I don't just want to hammer 'em, are you ready? Are you ready?
Are you ready?
I'll do a Google search and look for something interesting in their niche.
Maybe if it's a real estate guy like ai some kind of new AI thing for
the niche or whatever and just send him a link, be like,
Hey saw this au check this out and just leave it at that.
Just to pop up to the top of his inbox and be useful and productive but not keep
hammering him. So I, I like to do that. Okay,
That's awesome. And so the fact that he asked for a W nine uh like you said,
maybe they're just like obviously there's still hope,
like that's a good sign off. Yeah,
No a hundred percent I would say it's going to close.
It's just a matter when when sometimes that's outside of your control and
that's,
that is the tough part about sales sometimes is realizing that everything we
went through obviously in this program is geared towards trying to get it done
quick. That's like open up with,
it's just stuff that's outside of our control and their control too.
Especially the bigger the company like the more bureaucracy do this consulting
deal, this company that I work with,
it took almost a year and a half to get the deal done like that.
That's not an exaggeration. I'm very close friends with them personally.
So it wasn't, I wasn't going through what you were going through,
I knew it was going to get done, it was up just like I'm on their time.
And when you're a company that's going through hyper growth these things
and that's why I like harp on s e o so much too because when you get started in
SS e o you think SEO's the whole world and it's the most important thing in the
whole world.
But as you start to build your own business you realize we don't even do ss e o
for ourselves. So how important is it really?
So there's so much that goes into running a business.
There's first of all there's so much that goes into marketing SEO o's just one
facet it and there's so much that goes into marketing and sales and then people
and businesses and like they have their own customers they have to worry about
too their own product.
There's just a lot of moving pieces that go into running a business obviously.
So sometimes you know, just a healthy dose of patients is all you can do.
And again,
when you have this one deal that you've been like f**k this is the biggest deal
I'll ever close, it's gonna create some anxiety for you.
But as you get into this more and you have more deals, more hands in the fire,
it becomes a little bit easier to stomach when people do this to you.
So just keep focused on filling my pipeline,
have patience and maybe follow up like once a week and
Now follow up once a week with him, give him his space, give him his time.
You don't wanna be too pushy and too annoying but at the same time like you do
want to stay on top of him because if not he could
float away.
He could just get so busy where he is like this is just no longer priority for
me. And it happens to me all the time too. And that's the thing too,
it's like with anything that the further away you get a,
the further away that you get from like the point of interest,
the harder it can get for them to close. So you want to keep bringing him in,
like getting him locked at least in a place where he's still thinking about it.
He's still in his mind, he's still telling you yes, I'm still interested.
'cause if you just let them float away,
then like we'll just convince themselves they'll be like yeah we're fine,
we don't really need this anyways.
Which is probably gonna end up happening with these video editors.
For me unfortunately because I've already got a video editing place in company,
should I send
An email like that one, two or three option or is that maybe not now.
Maybe wait has only been like a week.
Yeah I would say that he hasn't exhibited that type of beha.
Like for me the 1, 2, 3 is I sent you a proposal and you haven't even told me
anything about it. I haven't heard.
Once it gets to the agreement phase it's a little bit different.
Like once they accept the proposal then it's okay I can pull back the breaks a
little bit.
But like the key with the follow-ups is getting them to make a decision about
whether or not they wanna work with you.
Which it sounds like he made that decision that he wants to work with you now.
It's just a matter of logistically and organizationally like getting everything
in the right place to do that. So like that can be a little bit,
I think again for me like it's, I,
I always think of these law firms that like I do all this work for them and then
I get down to the place where they're,
they asked for the proposal that they asked for is just,
they just f*****g ghosted on me and that's when I'm like, yo,
if you're not interested let me make this as easy for you as possible. One,
two or three.
Yeah that's really helpful. I I really appreciate it man.
Of course Andrew asked how long does Google keep historical
URL URLs around for after create a new site so you can recover old URLs with
a 3 0 1. I mean if it's completely deleted,
not long like I would say until they like Google won't keep a
deleted 4 0 4 in the index, right?
Because as soon as they crawl it then they'll understand that's a 4 0 4 and then
probably send the soda so I a notification and they'll take it out.
But that doesn't mean that, so for example,
referring to what Nester was talking about, right with those old URLs,
I'll still go through and redirect them even if they're no longer indexed just
because that would then push through and if the links that are pointing to
it are still indexed, then Google will still crawl that eventually.
So it's just kind of that history
Will still be there.
The, the history in terms of the ranking,
I don't know about that but let's say for example a client deleted like a whole
folder subfolder of pages, right? Products, services, whatever.
Let's say all those pages had external links pointing to them, right?
Those pages that they deleted will get removed from Google's index pretty
quickly 'cause Google will never wanna send somebody to a 4 0 4 page.
That experience.
However the links that are pointing to it on those pages are still probably
indexed,
which means the link pointing to that page like Google will crawl it but
probably won't re-index that page if it's 4 0 4.
But if you redirect it then it will push the equity as those other pages links
are getting crawled into the new page.
So like four oh fours I think are a little bit overrated as like a 4 0 4 cleanup
3 0 1 if it's a dead page with no links and it's deleted no matter how much
traffic it had, like once it's outta the index, it's no longer valuable.
It's only if that page has on the page then you just wanna clean that up and
redirect it in.
Andrew also said Michael did you add an expiration date to your offer?
It's really important to maybe talk about the opportunity cost delaying
starting. Yeah, that's what we alluded to, that the team is ready.
You know like we're assembled, like we're ready to get started.
The longer we wait, I just think uh, just based on what you told me Michael,
I would just be a little bit more patient with it. These things can take months.
As long as he's like still communicating with you a little bit and being like,
yeah I'm interested, don't worry then I wouldn't sweat it. Uh,
Andrew also said important to try and figure out the real reason for delay
important but ca is cashflow tight important but not urgent important but just
delaying until cashflow improves. Yeah, all the above. Yeah,
thanks Noah For the traffic projection that's in dev,
a bunch of those things are already being corrected with the filters,
all that stuff.
We also just put support in our comment to it too so we can communicate directly
with it.
Noah said when buying old expired sites and rebuilding the old missing pages,
they seem to still pass juice after the rebuild even if the site has been gone
for a year or two. Yeah, it's a worthwhile exercise. I,
when it comes to shortlist of technical things that I think are important,
I think cleaning up four or four pages is still on that list.
At least reviewing them because you see it all the time with companies if they
don't have pro like people just don't know either, right?
I'm going through this now with this really big company where they just,
I'm just finding out now like a couple months in that they've like continuously
changed URL structures like without doing anything just it's like okay,
like you were linking to it from your social media bio but like you're just
gonna change the U R L 'cause you thought it was cuter. Like I it just,
but they don't know,
they don't understand the impact that has and that can become a mess to clean
up.
You've really gotta comb through analytics to see that that's the only way you
see, you're like oh that page looks familiar, it's just really annoying.
But we're going through that now.
And then also just like cleaning up redirect hops,
like all that different stuff.
I just think that Google likes like a nice clean organized experience when these
things in the macro are pretty micro but when you put together like a couple of
micro things it can become pretty macro if that makes sense. Cool. Anybody else?
Everybody else got something they wanna chat about something on their mind.
We've been spending a good amount of stuff with the new Google AI stuff and
actually feeling more and more bullish about it.
Like actually like realizing I'm trying to like thinking in if I would actually
use it as a searcher and the jury's out a little bit for me,
I don't know if it's that much better of an experience maybe for some things
like certain types of queries and I think that's what we'll find is that like
the AI will be more available for certain types of queries. Again,
I think of stuff like recipes all the time.
There's certain things that I started using chat g p T for over Google and
that's things like recipes, things like, I don't know like basic q and a stuff.
But again stuff that just has really no impact on any sort of client businesses.
Actually it's recorded a video today where I was talking about the the top
bottom up approach to keyword research and just making sure to prioritize though
based on what the client needs and also then potentially integrating other
services to really get visibility for those. Go ahead Connor,
I didn't mean to interrupt you whenever you're done. Oh no I'm good. Okay.
Could you,
would you role play with me or walk me through how you would like
pitch to or what you would scope for a couple different clients?
A couple different types of clients.
Yeah,
One is like a purely e-commerce winery.
So think they're basically only selling their wine on online,
be it brand marketing or like distribution.
Mm-hmm And the other one would be how you,
how would you scope and sell like a local a more
localized SS e o pitch for someone that's, that's really their bread and butter.
It's just like local tasting your business.
We kind of talked about this a little bit.
Let me send the guess to start for local.
What are the things that you would focus on doing
on the initial setup and then on a more ongoing basis?
Because right now I've been selling local SS e o as a one-time
optimization.
It's definitely something that is normally ongoing too
because of the reviews, the Google posts and stuff like that.
But I figured if I could just optimize the profile first that's gonna be more
valuable and then I can get a grade in there and then try to get a more ongoing
contract with the local stuff.
Yeah, so with local in terms of making it ongoing,
there's things that like we're actually working on doing now which is like
review automation.
So like anytime they get a new customer they get audit like an N P S email
asking 'em about their experience and then asking them to prompt. There's also,
I actually got a TikTok out about it,
about like this like bump card that you can like have in wineries where you can
just like bump it and they can get a review.
So like you just bump a card and they literally triggers a review prompt on
their phone. So like review automation is one.
I would then also say like regular updates on their G B P profile in terms of
statuses, in terms of we're talking about, okay see what you're saying.
And then a link building is another part of it too, right?
Making sure that they have local links, citations, et cetera.
And then any content that would be needed for it as well. So location pages,
what we talked about last time, right?
With no we were going through and looking at like frequently asked questions
just on-page optimization, stuff like that.
So there's plenty there to make it like either a,
just a retainer like monthly where you do like regular things on a regular basis
or to scope it out like a sprint where you just then push it out over time.
But local's also something that's like very common in the market to just be like
500, 1500 a month, whatever that is for like local optimizations.
I think it's also important too that talking about making something recurring,
you have to be doing something on a regular basis but also if you're able to get
the results and people usually don't,
aren't paying attention to it 'cause they're looking at it much more.
So a good example is actually Cesar and I were talking for a long time last week
about how we could build a process potentially even like partnering with real
estate firms to just to find like very low cost true office space to get
verified locations for law firms, right?
And then that basically becomes what they're paying us for.
We just go to them and we're like just cold being like,
hey big pi firm with your internal marketing manager.
Like contact that person and be like, yo,
like we noticed that you operate in Vegas but you don't have a verified location
in Henderson.
Like we get like we will get you a verified office location there
at 5,000 bucks a month and optimize it to rank first and then as soon as they
stop paying us, we pull the location from them. Haven't gotten there yet,
but it's like something that I'm thinking about it's,
and it's not unsimilar too, they obviously have a verified location but it's,
once you get that result then it's just not uncommon for that. Okay.
So for the e-comm focus one dude, honestly let me look at the website.
To me like the only real play here is influencers because I don't think you can
pay for traffic for alcohol on most platforms.
I don't know if I'm wrong or right about that,
but I don't know if you can do like Facebook ads but even that it's like
To me you can, it's just tricky.
Yeah and it's also like people aren't just gonna see a bottle to me to really
sell wine you have to understand why people buy wine and like the
wine is just a very complicated,
it's a complicated sell because for the most part,
like I said like it's easier to,
it's much easier to sell your brand's wine when you're like somebody's on your
property. Like looking at the view, having an experience,
a memorable experience.
'cause not even that but like all wine like branding looks the same.
It's very complicated. Like you have to be like a wine,
true wine I'd walk into a wine store and be like, oh this,
it just doesn't happen. Yeah.
So like the only way to really do that would be influencers,
which is just a very expensive process. But
One the plays with this with the McBride sisters is they have a pretty
big brand. They've been around for 15, 20 years and they just,
they're one of the few like black women owned wine brands and so
like a, they don't really need tasting rooms, at least they haven't thus far.
And so like it's not,
obviously people wanna taste the wine first but it's more like they're buying
because they like the owners and like what the brand stands
For. Yeah, I get that.
So I'm looking at Arus now with their keywords and this kind of just is
what it is situation. 'cause what are you gonna do?
You're gonna optimize for like black owned wine. It's not really like a,
that's not really like a keyword. Yeah, yeah.
But like when you look at their top pages here and you look at like their
branded and you see how much brand like black girl Magic wine,
eight and a half thousand searches per month.
What might be interesting though is if you go to them and you talk to them about
just for your knowledge and understanding like what have you guys done?
What have you ladies done to generate this type of brand search and reach an
awareness.
'cause that might be something you can learn from and maybe open in the future.
But I would imagine it's probably coming from social media, right? Yeah.
Let's see their Instagram here,
they probably got like over a hundred thousand followers I would imagine. Yeah,
exactly. Pete, this is like a very long expensive process.
Like what you might be able to do with them.
Did they come to you or you came to them? How did this relationship start?
They work with a guy,
a website builder that I partner with to in the process of rebuilding their
website. Okay. They want, we're gonna throw them some ss e o into the deal.
Yep, that's fair. So what I would do then is I would,
I'm not saying that you can't work with 'em, right?
I just think that going with the traditional kind of,
I'm gonna make you more money it directly,
this is much more of an indirect campaign. Yeah.
So I would say product pages layouts like this page, these pages suck, right?
Maybe the designer's taking care of that already,
but you should be there to like influence,
influence what the design and stuff looks like.
The other thing would be the blog. So you can see that origin of sangria,
like we can look at all these are all branded keywords, right?
But origin of sangria, again what's the impact of this?
But helping them out with their content, it's not unimportant, right?
If they're willing to invest in it, then I would take the money.
But I would say that content would be the other big thing here.
So it'd be like influencing the proper architect and then just like content,
like more of 2018 SS e o which would be like content marketing.
'cause like this content isn't very good but it's like helping them understand
how they can use content maybe to influence their sales a little bit more in
terms of like more mid funnel content. Like this is not like for what?
Yeah and that could be a pitch too. I, you could go to 'em and be like,
you spent all this time and money on this content and like what is it doing for
your business? Like why are you creating this
Like realistically some pretty boring foundational technical
page stuff And then some foundational content marketing.
Yeah, some content strategy for sure. What does findel taste like? Yeah,
like this one's a little bit better but it's not deep enough and it's also not
personal enough. What I would make,
what I would pitch them right would be like look,
clearly this brand runs through you ladies.
I would say what we wanna try and do is we wanna try and impart the same level
of like personalization and on of your Instagram and social into your written
content, right?
Because this is their guide to Zinfandel and there's no pictures of them.
They should be like drinking the wine. There should be a video on here,
you know what I'm saying?
So much more like holistic blog content strategy where you can info decisions in
branding and purchasing a lot more. Also too,
just like this is a guide to zandel,
but like why don't they have any of those zandel?
There should be like a list of the zin that they sell on this page too.
Yeah, product features.
Yep. Yeah,
like an example of that too is we're doing with this client f e s lighting,
right?
So we're in the process of building product pages for them because they do,
so they offer a service but they have the products, the lights,
but they don't sell them directly.
So we're building them out as product pages but get a quote instead of buy,
right?
So what that allows us to do is allows us to go out and capture searches that
are more B two C but then hopefully try and convert them into B two B, right?
That's one.
Two is then we take those and now like our blog content that they have here,
which would be, which is not very good, but something like this one, right?
Like gym lighting, right? L e d lights for gyms.
Like we now have products that we can put images on here and then internally
link to the pages that are like the best lights for gyms, right?
So it allows us to build a lot more depth and a lot more relevance into the
content that they have and improve it just by making that switch.
It's like kind of something similar here.
They probably already have the content done the products,
but like they just are not implementing the right strategy here. And again,
they should be on video, there should be pictures of them,
they should be I that's what I would pitch them really.
I would be like maybe more of a fully integrated,
looks like they don't have a YouTube channel either, but, but yeah,
I would just say like making their blog much more personal and impactful if
you'll,
Okay. Okay. So for the big e-commerce brands, like,
and I know that you don't really work a lot with e-commerce but that's going to
be more like boring, technical, a lot of technical ss,
e o stuff and then content really. Yeah, it seems like.
Yeah. Yeah. See like just looking at their website, right? This is,
or their keyword rankings,
it's just really hard to get them to rank and it is like getting
a wine company to rank for white Zinfandel. It's just
Not gonna happen. Yeah, possible.
Not impossible if you get the right client. Absolutely. It's if you go,
if we apply, it's like the apparel market too. It's if you're like gap,
yeah absolutely. We can rank you for jeans 'cause you're in a,
you're in a top level class competition. But if you're like sure
You're
Just, you just sell jeans and this is your first website. Absolutely not.
Like you gotta take the route that these sisters did,
which is like put in the time to PR influencers build the brand product search
first and now like with the amount of searching that they have,
like there's an opportunity for them of course to rank for other stuff.
But the majority,
What are the local SS e o things that you mentioned?
I was just trying to write those down.
The local SS e o ones was automating reviews or like review generation.
What are they like posts on G B P I think they're called posts, right?
Like status updates, whatever.
So answering the questions that people are asking,
like citation builds like directories,
link building and then like localized content too for the website
Or citations. Isn't that more of just like a onetime thing because there's,
Yeah, it's a onetime thing.
Okay.
Okay. It's but like, you know what I'm saying? I'm just,
in order to turn this into recurring you can just list these things out and be
like this is what we're doing on a monthly basis.
I don't think that these types of clients at the retainers we'll be charging
will be like nitpicking you on it. Like I said,
most of this to me is about getting the results and then I, I,
I don't wanna tell you to lie to people are like pulled over their eyes but like
in certain industries, especially for what you're gonna charge for,
I don't really see an issue with being like this is an ongoing service once
you're ranked too. We're doing this every month. I don't know,
I guess it's not the most ethical thing to do per se, but it's, I'm
There for them to make sure this is happening and working and a resource.
Yeah, a hundred percent.
Okay. Alright, thanks
Ron. Cool. Anyone else?
Austin asked can we do a high level walkthrough for local Falcon
and potentially SEMrush like we did for Arus?
I don't have SEMrush unfortunately. Local
Falcon's fine. Okay. I just wanted to, nothing doesn't have to be too crazy.
I just wanted to see if there are just a couple like bullet points of like
things that I should, if I take this website where, what's the, what are two,
three steps can I take to get the information I need?
So local Falcon, I just pop it open. What do I do with this? Run a scan.
What's this company called? Countryside Roofing Scans. All right.
So it's gonna run the scans and then Yeah,
when you just click on them it'll show you.
So is there something specific in here that you wanted to
Yeah,
just like what I know they're gonna run the scans and then I'll be able to see
whether they're ranking or not in certain areas or on their specific section.
But I don't know,
is there any like specific data points that I need to hit or things I need to
find within this that would like in a one minute time period that I'd be able to
like give them value right off the bat using the tool?
So with local Falcon, not so much. I don't,
and I don't know what SEMrush is either. I dude,
I signed up for SEMrush a couple months ago and I tried to get back into it but
I was really annoyed with how like they make you pay for like every single
module in there now. It's actually really annoying.
They literally make you pay for to unlock everything in there.
And so like the core tool is the same as agere. There's not so much there.
I dunno if you're talking about like the local section in there. I tested,
I was gonna test it but they like it's much more expensive.
But this to me is purely a
visualization and
demonstration and understanding too. Because for example,
sometimes they're crushing it but so to go through and just show them where and
how they're performing and then really just the data that comes out of this is
just when they're not ranking well. Right.
Let me see if I can view the scan report.
So this just now gives me the ability to go in and pitch our service as
a solution for this.
There's nothing really hyper-specific here that you can glean from this.
Aside from the fact of like where they're not ranking,
the next thing to do is pull is just pull up their G B P profile and see where
they're deficient. Okay. So for example, so roofing contract,
let's see how they're doing here. So roofing,
they're doing pretty well within a small radius but on on the outskirts they're
not right. So that's roofing. Then for siding. Siding they're doing much better.
You can see. So I would just pull all these and just show them.
And then window installation, it looks like they're doing the worst. Yeah,
so what this tells me right is when I just look at
their G V P, they're just over-optimized for all.
Like you're just not gonna rank for all these roofing siding,
windows are especially windows.
Like it looks like you might be able to get away with roofing and siding as one,
but like they're probably gonna need a separate G B P or a separate targeting
here. Or maybe just adding additional categories.
I don't know if I can see the categories on the front end. The products here,
they're actually pretty well optimized. Yeah,
they're pretty well optimized here, but windows are just a,
another whole big one. Windows is a huge industry too,
especially here in Florida where they're all impacted.
You gotta have a dedicated G B P I would say for this.
And then roofing is also another huge one obviously too.
And it is like the old school aaa,
like they almost named this business for SS e O purposes.
But yeah here I would say that they're probably gonna have to get another G B P
maybe to go after the alternate keyword. Um,
which would be windows or, because you can just see,
I mean this one's just not ranking well in comparison to windows and siding.
So I would just, I would take this one in probably go after roofing and siding,
but specifically roofing. 'cause that's gonna be the biggest,
most profitable keyword for them 'cause it's huge.
And then you're gonna have to figure out something else for like window
installation,
whether that's another G V P or also new markets too. Right.
So let's see where they are on a, yeah,
so if you could get them in different markets too.
It looks like they're in the sticks out here in a smaller region, smaller area.
Do you have any other questions on that? That's kind,
that's no use local falcon for Yeah that was good to see how they're performing.
'cause like looking at G B P, you obviously you can search for it manually, but,
but I'll just use it as a jumping off point to then.
I mean they have a good profile here and the thing is too, man,
as I'm finding is I like most companies do now,
like optimizing your G V P is so simple that most companies come in with a
pretty good optimized profile. It's just a small thing.
Like this is their business name. So it's a little bit tough.
But you can see here that, let's see if they have,
so the other thing too is I would say is that maybe, so if we go to Streamwood,
Illinois, we'll call this wind, I dunno, window replacement. Yeah,
I might pitch them LSAs then instead. Or local ads which are down here.
So these are actually tied into here.
So this is like a hack that we're finding that is if if you can't get them a
different, if you can't get them a different profile,
if you can't change the relevancy of it,
then just bidding on the keywords here organically is, I'm sorry,
with paid in the local ads, crushes it.
This is a really good placement here too. Literally just hack to get to the top.
Do you guys do paid too, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah. With stuff like this,
it's again,
what we're trying to look here for is the last thing that we wanna do is walk
into pitch and be like, Hey, you're doing good. Yeah.
You always wanna come in with your audio cut out. Can you guys hear me? Yeah.
Yeah. Okay, cool. Yeah, so in this case it's, it's not a bad thing, right?
To just come in and be like, look, our goal here is to get you leads, right?
It's not necessarily to just rank you first here.
So what we can do is we can definitely rank you first for roofing contractor by
just like retiming your G V P profile and focusing on that and then picking up
leads there organically.
And then we can do a paid campaign to pick up the visibility for
the window installation as well with LSAs and local ads.
And then also a traditional SS e o campaign on the rest of the website too to
just rank it for, yeah,
It doesn't seem to be ranking very well for a lot of stuff,
but they've been in business for 50 years and they have a ton of good reviews.
So just seemed like good opportunity. Yeah.
Let's see. Yeah, they're not ranking too well. Yeah. So they did this,
you see the title here? Siding company near me.
It looks like they got in with a S E O company who wasn't maybe the smartest.
Does anybody here, I'm not a huge fan of putting near me as a title.
Who here does a lot of local, but yeah, I would just like this too. Like the,
it's a bit of a reach. This is where I would focus your analysis on too,
is like helping them refocus and retarget their, their pages,
their titles. The on page is just not right here. Okay,
Cool. Yeah, it was all good. I just was wondering what the stuff Yeah, no,
think about, but thank you. No worries.
Of course. Anyone else? Alright. All right. Okay, cool.
So if you all have more questions,
if you all want to do another one of these sessions, I'm happy to,
this is technically the last one that we have, but if there's anything else,
like I said,
I'm here to make sure that everyone here has been helped as best I can.
Go ahead Andrew, just
A quick question. Where are you pulling your traffic protection numbers from?
Is it Ah, refs?
No, it's SEMrush.
That's SEMrush. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. We use their A P I, but I don't use their, because HS a p I is,
s**t, it doesn't give us the same type of,
they're like super protective over the traffic estimates.
They'll give you their link data but not their traffic estimate
Data.
And do I send you a private message to get the discount code or we set that up?
Yeah, make sure to dmm me. We'll get that. We'll get that for you guys for sure.
Okay.
Just need to set that up on my to-do list word. All right. This has been,
I think you had mentioned that y you or Elena or Anne was gonna put together a
like how to do your C R M and how to manage that. Yep.
Is that still in the books or? It is,
Yeah. I'm waiting on to record the video. She was on vacation? Yeah,
she was on vacation for a while. Oh cool. Cool. Yeah,
these are all helpful things.
Just make sure you post all this stuff in the Slack channel so that way Anne and
Elena see it. They help me keep everything organized, so just drop it in there.
We can also do soon on our live session,
it probably might be the easiest version, run through how to do it,
because recording video can take a lot longer. So Yeah,
That's fine.
Happy to add that on. There's a long session, so yeah,
if anything else that we missed,
please drop it in Slack and we'll make sure to either put together another
session, some videos, the codes,
whatever you guys need to make sure that we get,
get everything that you all need. Awesome. All right. This has been fun guys.
We will, uh, we'll talk soon. All right. Thank
You. Yeah.
Bye guys. You.